Inventory of the Psi Upsilon Records, 1840 - 1972
Psi Upsilon Records1840 - 1972
- Series III. Correspondence, 1881-1971
  - Letter boxes
    - Chapter letters
      - Special, 1892-1916 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
      - A, 1898-1903 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - B, 1897-1903 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - C, 1897-1903 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - D, 1899-1916 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - E, 1897-1916 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - F, 1898-1903 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - G, 1898-1903 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - H, 1899-1916 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - I-J, 1898-1916 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - K, 1897-1903 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - L, 1898-1916 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - M, Undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Mc, 1898-1902 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - O, 1898-1916 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - P-Q, 1897-1916 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - R, 1899-1903 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - S, 1899-1903 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - T, 1899-1916 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - U-V, 1898-1916 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - W, 1898-1903 (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - X-Z, 1898-1903 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Series IV. Scrapbooks, 1863-1901
  - Psi Upsilon scrapbook, about 1863-1885 (Box 15)
    Blue pages, several detached sections.
  - Psi Upsilon scrapbook, about 1884-1901 (Box shelf)
  - Psi Upsilon scrapbook, about 1891-1901 (Box 15)
- Series V. Members1844-1936
  - List of fraternity officers for 1897, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report of the Xi Chapter to the Executive Council of the Psi Upsilon Fraternity, including membership list, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Handwritten list of members and tallies of awards received from 1844-1873, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Catalogue of the Psi Upsilon Fraternity, 1870 (Box 14)
    Catalogue of members
  - Catalogue of the Psi Upsilon Fraternity, June 1849 (Box 14)
    Cover titled "Zeta Chapter," catalogue of members
  - Catalogue of the Psi Upsilon Fraternity, March 1879 (Box 14)
    catalogue of members
  - Catalogue of the Psi Upsilon Fraternity, 1849 (Box 14)
  - Supplement to the Eleventh General Catalogue of the Psi Upsilon Fraternity, 1908 (Box 14)
  - Twelfth General Catalogue of the Psi Upsilon Fraternity, 1917 (Box 14)
- Series VI. Initiations, 1890-1971
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, October 10-11, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, November 2, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, November 2, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, September 28, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, November 18, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, November 3, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, November 9, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, November 14, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, November 7, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, February 22, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, November 8, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, February 27, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, February 18, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, June 14, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, June 12, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, February 19, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, February 18, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Announcement of new initiates, February 17, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, February 17, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, February 15, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, February 15, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, February 15, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, September 16, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, September 16, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Program for annual ititiation ceremony, November 5, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series VII. Programs and Events, 1868-1938
  - Annual Exercises of the Wesleyan University, 1868 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Announcement of the Seventh Quadrennial Exercises, June 24, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Program for the Seventh Quadrennial Exercises, June 24, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Program for the Seventh Quadrennial Exercises, June 24, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Duplicate
  - Announcement of the Forty-Fourth Annual Convention of the Psi Upsilon Fraternity, about 1877 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Public Exercises of the Forty-Fourth Annual Convention, May 10, 1877 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Order of Exercises for the Eighth Quadrennial, June 26, 1877 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Announcement of the annual reception, June 24, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Program for the Parlor Concert, May 5, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Order of Exercises for the Ninth Quadrennial, June 27, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Order of Exercises for the Ninth Quadrennial, June 27, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Public Exercises for the Semi-Centennial Anniversary, May 24, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Initiation Exercises, September 26-27, 1884 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Program for the musical accompaniment to the initiation ritual, September 26-27, 1884 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Annual Exercises of the Wesleyan University, 1868 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Program for the Parlor Concert, May 14, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Program for the Annual Musicale, March 23, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Ninth Quinquennial Exercises, June 27, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Program for the Fifty-Seventh Annual Convention, May 1-2, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Program for the Amateur Theatricals, May 19, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Program for Psi Upsilon event including an orchestral show, May 6, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for Amateur Theatricals, May 26, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for Amateur Theatricals, May 23, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for Amateur Theatricals, May 24, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Announcement of unknown Psi Upsilon event including a musicale, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for Annual Musicale, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for Seventy-Fifth Anniversary of the Xi Chapter, June 16, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for Seventy-Fifth Anniversary of the Xi Chapter, June 16, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for Annual Musicale, June 23, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for musical event at Psi Upsilon, June 21, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for Annual Musicale, undated, about 1920 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Announcement of an unknown event at Psi Upsilon, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for the 87th Annual Convention of the Psi Upsilon Fraternity, May 5-7, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for musical event at Psi Upsilon, June 18, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for Annual Musicale, June 17, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for Annual Musicale, June 19, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Nametag belonging to R. P. Harrington from the Centennial Convention of Psi Upsilon, November 24, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    First of two nametags belonging to R. P. Harrington
  - Nametag belonging to R. P. Harrington from the Centennial Convention of Psi Upsilon, November 24, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Second of two nametags belonging to R. P. Harrington
  - Program for the Psi Upsilon Centennial Banquet, November 24, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for Centennial Festival of the Chique Chaque Club, November 12, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for a production of "In the Zone" by Eugene O'Neill, February 22, ? (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Empty envelope addressed to Prof. and Mrs. Rice, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Empty envelope stamped with the crest of the Xi Chapter of Psi Upsilon, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Small tag listing members of a reception committee for an unknown event, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Small tag listing members of a reception committee for an unknown event, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Inivation to Xi Chapter Annual Reception, June 24, 1890 (Box 12)
- Series VIII. Music and Poetry 1877-1970
  - "America," by George W. Elliott, February 28, 1883 (rewritten 1890) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "The Banner of Psi U," by George W. Elliott, June 15, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Chapter House Song," by Mills Whittlesey, March 5, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "The Bugle Call," by Richard B. Turiss, May 5, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Chapter House Song," by Mills Whittlesey, September 26, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Commemorative Ode," by Frank N. Mandeville and George W. Elliott, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Reveries of Psi Upsilon," by George W. Elliott, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Letter to Karl Harrington containing verses of the Psi Upsilon marching song, March 27, 1891 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Calcium Light," undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "The Ever-Lovely Maiden," undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Carmen Ad Psi Upsilon," undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Carmen Ad Psi Upsilon," undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Carmen Ad Psi Upsilon," undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Includes one more verse than other copies of "Carmen Ad Psi Upsilon"
  - "The Man Who Thinks He Can," undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "The Teetotallers are Coming," undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    On back: "Our Home is Bright Again" and "Weep For the Fallen!"
  - "Psi U," by Charles Robinson, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Includes two staffs of handwritten sheet music
  - "A Summer Night," by Paul Siegvolk, with an envelope addressed to Karl Harrington from Albert Matthews, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Psi Upsilon Reunion Song," by Albert Tolman, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Sumus in Spe," by C. W. Winchester, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "? of Middle Age," undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Psi U Wanderlied," undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Come, All Ye Joyful-Hearted," by Prosser Hall Frye, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "A Voice is Sounding Through the Branches," undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "While Youth Ever Tells...," by C. F. Johnson, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Museation Hymn," by Emory J. Haynes, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Memorial Ode," by George W. Elliott, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Invocation Hymn," by George W. Elliott, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "The Ship Psi U," by W. Whitman Bailey, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "The Origin of Psi Upsilon," undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "The Candidates' Song," undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Yale Songs-Xi of Psi Upsilon by Francis B. Kellogg and Thomas G. Shepard, 1889 (Box 13)
  - Songs of the Psi Upsilon Fraternity, 1945 (Box 13)
    Twelfth Edition
  - Songs of the Psi Upsilon Fraternity, 1903? (Box 13)
  - Songs of the Psi Upsilon Fraternity, 1891 (Box 13)
  - Songs of Psi Upsilon, undated (Box 13)
    3 copies, inside cover of one marked "Jesse Lyman Hurlbut, Class of 1864, Wesleyan University;" inside one is a letter from Hurlbut to the secretary of Psi Upsilon dated January 18, 1970
  - Songs of Psi Upsilon, 1877 (Box 13)
- Series IX. Clippings, 1891-1957
  - Issue of "The Middletown Herald," including section on college news at Wesleyan, June 23, 1891 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Issue of "The Concordiensis," including article titled "Psi U. Presents 'Seat of Stone,'" November 24, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Issue of "Schenectady Gazette," including article titled "1,000 Witness Psi U.'s Rites at Centennial," November 25, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Issue of "The Wesleyan Argus," including announcement of the death of James D. Sturgess '59, member of Psi Upsilon, May 17, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Issue of "The Wesleyan Argus," including announcement of the death of James D. Sturgess '59, member of Psi Upsilon, May 17, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series X. Publications, 1855-1953
  - Psi Upsilon Catalogue of all chapters and members, 1855 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "The Oration and Poem, Together with the Convention Song, and Extracts from the Proceedings of the Forty-Fourth General Convention of the Psi Upsilon Fraternity," 1877 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "The Psi Upsilon at Wesleyan: A Chapter Letter to the Graduates of Xi," 1881-1882 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "The Xi News," December 1930 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Chapel Talk," by T. R. Bodine April 13, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "The Garnet and Gold: Xi of Psi Upsilon," 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Report on the Eclectic Society (Phi Nu Theta), undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Olla Podrida, 1868-1884 (Box 13)
  - Olla Podrida, 1896 (Box 13)
  - Olla Podridas No. 1-16, 1921 (Box 13)
  - The Wesleyan Song Book by Karl P. Harrington and Carl F. Price, 1906 (Box 14)
    Anniversary Edition
  - The Diamond of Psi Upsilon, November 1936 (Box 14)
    Official Fraternity Publication
  - A History of the Xi Chapter of the Psi Upsilon Fraternity by Karl Pomeroy Harrington, 1935 (Box 14)
  - The Psi Upsilon Epitome, 1884 (Box 14)
- Series XI. Photographs, 1871-1890
  - Photograph of L. N. Cummings, June 1871 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Photograph of George W. Shink, July 1871 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Photograph of Olin L. Livesey, about 1873 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Photograph of Joseph Bunker, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Three unlabeled portraits of a Psi Upsilon member, about 1871 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Aerial photograph of Wesleyan campus, with view of College Row, Andrus Field, and observatory, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Group photograph of Psi Upsilon members, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Group photograph of Class of 1885 members of Psi Upsilon, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Group photograph of Psi Upsilon members all dressed in a white cloth, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Four group photographs of Psi Upsilon members, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Xi chapter of Psi Upsilon Photo Album, undated (Box 12)
  - Oversize group portrait, about 1890 (Box 16)
- Series XII. Other Records, 1840-1933
  - The Classic; or College Monthly, July 1, 1840 (Box 14)
- Series XIII. Architectural Drawings, May 1891
  - New Chapter House, Middletown, Conn. by Colin C. Wilson, May 1891 (Box oversize)
    1/4 Scale plan of foundations and drainage
  - New Chapter House, Middletown, Conn. by Colin C. Wilson, May 1891 (Box oversize)
    Plan of roof, plan of look-out, third floor plan
  - New Chapter House, Middletown, Conn. by Colin C. Wilson, May 1891 (Box oversize)
    Plan of site
  - New Chapter House, Middletown, Conn. by Colin C. Wilson, May 1891 (Box oversize)
    Section on line C.D., section on line AmB
  - New Chapter House, Middletown, Conn. by Colin C. Wilson, May 1891 (Box oversize)
    South elevation, east elevation
  - New Chapter House, Middletown, Conn. by Colin C. Wilson, May 1891 (Box oversize)
    North elevation facing College Street, West elevation facing High Street
  - New Chapter House, Middletown, Conn. by Colin C. Wilson, May 1891 (Box oversize)
    First floor plan, second floor plan, plan gallery
  - New Chapter House, Middletown, Conn. by Colin C. Wilson, May 1891 (Box oversize)
    Basement Plan